Trent Collection on Franklin Delano Roosevelt, 1945-1949
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Trent Collection on Franklin Delano Roosevelt 1945-1949
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Trent, Josiah and Mary Duke Biddle, collector
0.4 linear feet Extent: 12 Items
Josiah and Mary Duke Biddle Trent collected and donated the Trent Collection, including these materials on U.S. president Franklin Delano Roosevelt. Assorted printed materials about FDR, including his stamp collecting and obituary material; autographed portraits; and 2 signed letters from FDR dating from 1932 and 1933.
RL.01314
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Trent Collection on Franklin Delano Roosevelt was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift.
Historical Note
The Trent Collection on Franklin Delano Roosevelt was given to the Rubenstein Library as part of the Trent Collection by Josiah and Mary Duke Biddle Trent. It honors FDR, the 32nd president of the United States, who served in office from 1933 until his death in 1945.
Collection Overview
Collection includes printed materials about FDR, including obituary materials and articles about his stamp collecting. Also contains 2 autographed letters from 1932 and 1933, and 2 autographed portraits of FDR.
Subject Headings
Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945
Contents of Collection
- Trent Collection Materials, 1932-1946, (1 box)
  - Kinkead, Eugene. "The Great Philatelist," The New Yorker. 1946 March 30 (Box 1)
  - Repland, L. "A Humble Tribute to FDR," 1945 (Box 1)
  - Trinidad and Tobego stamps (4) (Box 1)
  - Sloane, George B. "The President Franklin D. Roosevelt Collection," Stamps. 1945 November 24. (Box 1)
  - Time Magazine issue re: FDR's death. 1945 April 23 (Box 1)
  - Facsimile, enlarged, of U.S. Savings Bond, $200. 1946 (Box 1)
  - Bush, Vannevar, OSRD. "Science: The Endless Frontier" report to the president, 1945 (Box 1)
  - 2 autographed letters from FDR, one as Governor of New York and one on White House stationary. 1932 and 1933 (Box 1)
  - National Citizens Political Action Committee circular, undated (post-1945) (Box 1)
  - Ludwig, Emil. "Roosevelt in War," Free World. 1946 May (Box 1)
  - U.S. Dept. of Justice. Memorial Service for FDR. 1945 April 13 (Box 1)
  - 2 autographed portraits of FDR (Box 1)
  - 1 autographed portrait of Eleanor Roosevelt (Box 1)
  - The New Republic, with Roosevelt supplements. 1946 April 15 and 1946 April 29 (Box 1)